# KUTALMIŞ BERKE YILMAZ

Mobile: +905448169364 | E-mail:kberkeyilmaz@gmail.com | GitHub | Personal App | LinkedIn

### **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Able software developer with experience in full-stack languages like **Next.Js** and **PHP**, also proficient in frontend languages like JavaScript(**React**, TypeScript, jQuery, Vanilla, Framer.motion, MaterialUI etc...), CSS(TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, SASS). Can work with SOAP and RESTful API's. Background in translation and tech management.

#### **SKILLS**

**Technical:** React.Js, Next.Js, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, SASS, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, HTML5, PHP, SQL. **Languages:** English (fluent), French (fluent), Turkish (native).

#### **EXPERIENCE**

- Frontend Web Developer, FioresGlobal (Remote) March 2023 July 2023
- Reengineered company's website to improve accessibility, responsiveness and user experience.
- Enhanced the organization's technical understanding by providing comprehensive insights about **APIs**, backend and frontend responsibilities and **UI/UX** principles.
- MySQL Server Administrator, Frontend Web Developer Mobilpark Communication Softwares (Hybrid) —
  September 2022- March 2023
- Offered consistent customer support and handled client trainings.
- Reinvented the **dashboard design**, emphasizing brand visibility and implemented customer feedback to improve application **UI**.
- Facilitated an increase in operational efficiency.
- Gained exposure to MVC fundamentals.
- Interpreter Ithaki Publishing 2020-2022
- Translations in Sci-fi genre.
- Content proofreading.
- Books to be published: Shrinking Man by Richard Matheson, Devolution by Max Brooks.
- CPU+ Senior Technical Expert, Project Leia, Webhelp Turkey 2018-2020
- Maintained 93% customer satisfaction score with 72% issue resolution over two years.
- Provided mentorship to entry level advisors, reported diverse hardware and software issues to engineering teams.
- Established a gourmet club with over **90 members** and spearheaded various food-oriented events.

### **EDUCATION**

- Interpretation and Translation in French, Marmara University, Istanbul 2016
- Lycée Saint Joseph d'Izmir 2011

## **Certificates**

- Intro to Computer Science Certificate of Success, Izmir Economy University -2022
- DUOLINGO (IELTS EQUIVALENT), Overall Score: 140 (IELTS: C1) 2023
- DELPH, Overall Score: B2 2017
- IELTS Academic, Overall Score: 7,5 2016